Vincenzo Chiovaro

vincenzochiovaro194@gmail.com Manchester 07709 219 344 GitHub MyPortfolio LinkedIn

Personal Profile

Hi, I'm a graduate Full-Stack developer with experience in the JavaScript ecosystem, I believe that JavaScript is a great programming language, but I'm always open to changing my mind. Over the course of my learning journey, I have worked on a diverse range of projects, from designing and building RESTful Apis to creating front-end applications that consumes APIs and present data in engaging ways.

Skills

Back-end: Node, Express, PostgreSQL, REST API development, Experience with MVC design pattern

Front-end: React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript **Tools and Technologies:** Jest, Git, GitHub

Work History

11/2022 – 03/2023 Northcoders - Trainee Full-Stack Developer

Northcoders is an intensive, hands-on bootcamp focused on training full-stack developers. During the program, I received training in back-end and front-end development technologies and learned how to create full-stack web applications from scratch to deployment, using Agile methodologies.

- Developed a mobile application called **"Swapz"** as part of a team project using React Native and Expo Go. The app enables users to exchange goods and features a simple and intuitive user interface. Utilized Firebase as Backend-as-a-service for data storage, and image hosting. <u>Video Presentation-Link</u>
- Designed the **NC-Games** API with a RESTful architecture, enabling users to view, create, update and delete reviews and comments. Ensured easy integration with client-side applications and scalability for future expansion. *NC-Games-Link*
- Developed a front-end Genre Gaming Opinion Hub that connects to my back-end API to fetch data containing images of games with different categories. Users can view game reviews, leave comments, and interact with reviews trhoughl likes and GGOH-Link

2021 – Current Amazon - Amnesty Responder

- Monitor and follow up on trouble tickets in order to support the operation flow
- Collaborate with internal and external stakeholders to develop solutions ad action plans to address identified issues
- Conduct research to address shipping errors and packaging mistakes
- Troubleshot problems through to resolution, escalating to Area Manager or Reliability Maintenance Engineer as needed

05/2020 – 12/2020 Amazon - Problem Solver

- Replenished inventory with focus on addressing customer needs
- Investigated and resolve billing and service discrepancies
- Resolved customer issues using strong interpersonal skills and conflict resolution techniques
- Processed product returns and exchanges

07/2019 – 05/2020 Amazon - Picker and Packer

- Picked customer orders ensuring a high level of quality and productivity
- Ensured that the picked product conforms to the order sheet provided
- Accurately packed and shipped customer orders
- Adhered to strict safety, quality and production standards

Education

03/2022 – 08/2022 Pitman Training Centre - Web Developer Diploma

- Computer and Technology Basics for Developers
- JavaScript fundamentals
- HTML
- CSS/SCSS

09/2021 **CompTIA A+220-1001 Core 1**

- Understanding of cloud computing concepts, including Saas, IaaS and PaaS models
- Understanding of network architecture, protocols and devices, as well as network troubleshooting and security
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of operating systems, including Windows, macOS, Linux and mobile operating systems

2008 – 2013 Don Luigi Sturzo, Bagheria, Italy

A Levels (Equivalent) including Accounting, Maths, and Science

Interest and Hobbies

I enjoy engaging in a variety of interests and hobbies that contribute to my overall mental wellness. This includes regular exercise, such as **jogging**, as well as **staying up to date with the latest technology trends** through reading articles and watching videos. I also enjoy undertaking personal projects related to software development, such as **building web apps** or experimenting with new programming languages and frameworks.